<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Matt Hartz</title><link>https://matthartz.me/</link><description>Recent content on Matt Hartz</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://matthartz.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Goggins Razor</title><link>https://matthartz.me/posts/goggins_razor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthartz.me/posts/goggins_razor/</guid><description>David Goggins is the type of figure who I definitely would have hated 5 years ago if I had come across him. And I think that probably says more about what my mindset was than who he is(1). I would’ve seen him as some type of motivational grifter who would say anything to get people to buy what he is selling. And perhaps that might be true. But I don’t think it matters.</description></item><item><title>Identifying Suicidal Ideation</title><link>https://matthartz.me/posts/nlp_manu/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthartz.me/posts/nlp_manu/</guid><description>I had my first research paper published surrounding a lot of the work I have been doing at NeuroFlow. This was a new experience to me, and one that I learned a lot doing. Not only was this my first foray into any sort of research writing but I was also entrusted to be first author – an honor I would not have been able to handle if not for the endless support of everyone else involved.</description></item><item><title>2023 Reading List</title><link>https://matthartz.me/posts/books_2023/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthartz.me/posts/books_2023/</guid><description>Compiling the books I read in 2023, maybe someone will see this and it will spark a conversation about one of them. These are mostly in chronological order
The Body Keeps the Score by Bessel Van Der Kolk Incredible book. Something I think everyone can benefit from reading. Whether or not you have experiences with Depression, Anxiety, etc. there are many ways in which you can benefit from being more intune with what your body is telling you.</description></item><item><title>ChatGPT Tip: Ask for things to avoid</title><link>https://matthartz.me/posts/gpt_mistakes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthartz.me/posts/gpt_mistakes/</guid><description>Wanted to share a new prompt I&amp;rsquo;ve been using a lot with ChatGPT. It&amp;rsquo;s basically, &amp;ldquo;What are common mistakes people make when doing X&amp;rdquo;. I like it since it&amp;rsquo;s an easy way to double check yourself on certain things before diving in.
I&amp;rsquo;ve asked this for things like buying an insurance policy, cooking a new dish, doing some work around my house. Most of the time it doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily give me anything I don&amp;rsquo;t already know, but here and there I find it saved me.</description></item><item><title>How I Debug SQL</title><link>https://matthartz.me/posts/sql_debugging/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthartz.me/posts/sql_debugging/</guid><description>Debugging any type of code is frustrating and tedious. And since the most frequent and most dangerous SQL errors occur even when the code compiles, it can be hard to know where to start when attempting to debug. Moreover, it&amp;rsquo;s not always possible to have a strong instinct on whether or not the returned data is correct, making it all the more crucial to have a process for debugging and double checking your query.</description></item><item><title>Digital Minimalism</title><link>https://matthartz.me/posts/digital_ascetic/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthartz.me/posts/digital_ascetic/</guid><description>Recently, I’ve found myself in increasingly more discussions(arguments) on the merits of technology and social media[1]. In all of these discussions, people readily admit that their use of social media is too high, but we usually disagree on where the right amount of use lies.
I have to admit that I’ve started to become a bit of a digital ascetic &amp;ndash; at least an aspiring one. I feel like I have good reason, but one thing I’ve realized is I am not great at making my arguments.</description></item><item><title>Setting up a PyTorch Environment</title><link>https://matthartz.me/posts/anaconda_env/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthartz.me/posts/anaconda_env/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s no secret that setting up a development environment for Machine Learning is a nightmare. There are a lot of tools that try to abstract some of that complexity away, but it&amp;rsquo;s easy to still run into problems(1).
My tool of choice has been Anaconda. Is it the best? I have no idea, but it&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve become most comfortable with(2). I&amp;rsquo;ve banged my head against the wall enough times that I have finally found some success with it.</description></item><item><title>Future Nostalgia</title><link>https://matthartz.me/posts/future_nostalgia/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthartz.me/posts/future_nostalgia/</guid><description>Nostalgia is such a strange concept to me. As far as evolution goes, I have trouble trying to think of reasons for humans to need it. Was it some sort of mechanism to downshift the odds of someone leaving a tribe? I digress, examining the evolutionary development of nostalgia is not the reason for this post.
The reason for this post is that I enjoy nostalgia. The melancholy feelings it evokes within me when I think back on certain parts of my life fascinate me.</description></item><item><title>Nominal Mastery</title><link>https://matthartz.me/posts/nominal_mastery/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthartz.me/posts/nominal_mastery/</guid><description>As someone who loves trying to learn new things, I’ve always had trouble determining when I’ve “learned” that new thing. While learning something new can be fulfilling, it is rare for there to be that clear lightswitch moment of mastery. It is more often the case that as you progress in a certain domain you begin to find more and more subdomains that you had no prior knowledge of. What started as a simple desire to Learn How to Bake Bread might have you down a rabbit hole of different techniques, gadgets, and baking philosophies.</description></item><item><title>Books as a Social Network</title><link>https://matthartz.me/posts/books_as_a_service/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthartz.me/posts/books_as_a_service/</guid><description>Please Don't Sue Me Columbia Pictures
Pretend you’re at a party with a close friend of yours. They’re the only person you know there so of course they excuse themselves to go to the bathroom, leaving you standing there with a complete stranger in a you’re just now realizing how boring your shoes are kind of awkwardness.
Grasping at straws for common ground you talk about your backgrounds, and would you believe it you both went to the same small liberal arts school out in rural Nowhere.</description></item><item><title>NormConf 2022 Notes</title><link>https://matthartz.me/posts/normconf_2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthartz.me/posts/normconf_2022/</guid><description>I spent part of my holiday going through the backlog of all the great NormConf talks. There were some awesome topics discussed by some great folks in the data community. Tried to compile my notes and figured I&amp;rsquo;d post them here. I don&amp;rsquo;t have notes for every talk so be sure to check out https://normconf.com/ to find info on all the talks/speakers.
Two themes I found consistent throughout many of the talks:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://matthartz.me/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthartz.me/about/</guid><description>Hi, welcome to my personal site. My plan is to use this site in somewhat random ways. Sometime there will be content related to Data, sometimes it might be some rambling I have about the world, or any other thing that might interest me enough to write about. This site will probably stay pretty barebones outside of the written content, since it&amp;rsquo;s not really a focus to dedicate development time to it.</description></item></channel></rss>