<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matt Hartz</title>
    <link>https://matthartz.me/blog_hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Matt Hartz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://matthartz.me/blog_hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Books as a Social Network</title>
      <link>https://matthartz.me/blog_hugo/posts/books_as_a_service/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthartz.me/blog_hugo/posts/books_as_a_service/</guid>
      <description>Please Don&#39;t Sue Me Columbia Pictures
Pretend you’re at a party with a close friend of yours. They’re the only person you know there so of course they excuse themselves to go to the bathroom, leaving you standing there with a complete stranger in a you’re just now realizing how boring your shoes are kind of awkwardness.
Grasping at straws for common ground you talk about your backgrounds, and would you believe it you both went to the same small liberal arts school out in rural Nowhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NormConf 2022 Notes</title>
      <link>https://matthartz.me/blog_hugo/posts/normconf_2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthartz.me/blog_hugo/posts/normconf_2022/</guid>
      <description>I spent part of my holiday going through the backlog of all the great NormConf talks. There were some awesome topics discussed by some great folks in the data community. Tried to compile my notes and figured I&amp;rsquo;d post them here. I don&amp;rsquo;t have notes for every talk so be sure to check out https://normconf.com/ to find info on all the talks/speakers.
Two themes I found consistent throughout many of the talks:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nominal Mastery</title>
      <link>https://matthartz.me/blog_hugo/posts/nominal_mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthartz.me/blog_hugo/posts/nominal_mastery/</guid>
      <description>As someone who loves trying to learn new things, I’ve always had trouble determining when I’ve “learned” that new thing. While learning something new can be fulfilling, it is rare for there to be that clear lightswitch moment of mastery. It is more often the case that as you progress in a certain domain you begin to find more and more subdomains that you had no prior knowledge of. What started as a simple desire to Learn How to Bake Bread might have you down a rabbit hole of different techniques, gadgets, and baking philosophies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Debug SQL</title>
      <link>https://matthartz.me/blog_hugo/posts/sql_debugging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthartz.me/blog_hugo/posts/sql_debugging/</guid>
      <description>Debugging any type of code is frustrating and tedious. And since the most frequent and most dangerous SQL errors occur even when the code compiles, it can be hard to know where to start when attempting to debug. Moreover, it&amp;rsquo;s not always possible to have a strong instinct on whether or not the returned data is correct, making it all the more crucial to have a process for debugging and double checking your query.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://matthartz.me/blog_hugo/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthartz.me/blog_hugo/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, welcome to my personal site. My plan is to use this site in somewhat random ways. Sometime there will be content related to Data, sometimes it might be some rambling I have about the world, or any other thing that might interest me enough to write about. This site will probably stay pretty barebones outside of the written content, since it&amp;rsquo;s not really a focus to dedicate development time to it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
